<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dheeto Blog</title>
    <link>https://dheerapat.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dheeto Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© dheeto</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dheerapat.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modular Monolithic</title>
      <link>https://dheerapat.github.io/posts/modular-monolithic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dheerapat.github.io/posts/modular-monolithic/</guid>
      <description>The Ugly Duck When we talk about the word monolithic, many engineers have negative feelings about it. Some might say, &amp;ldquo;Expanding a monolithic application is very hard,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Maintaining a monolithic app is an exhausting task.&amp;rdquo; Often, we assume these claims are true simply because they relate to monolithic design. We frequently hear negative comments about monolithic architecture and praise another architecture, microservices, as if it&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate solution.&#xA;But what if I told you there are multiple ways to build a monolithic application, and if done correctly, it is much easier for a small team to maintain and expand these apps?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Drive with Linux</title>
      <link>https://dheerapat.github.io/posts/daily-drive-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dheerapat.github.io/posts/daily-drive-linux/</guid>
      <description>From the Beginning Getting software to work on Windows is an easy task: just click an installer, click the next button, let the installation bar run to 100%, and boom, you’ve installed software on a Windows machine. But when it comes to &amp;lsquo;development tools&amp;rsquo; such as Docker, compilers, Kubernetes, etc., you will find that installing these tools on Windows is quite complex and not so straightforward.&#xA;That’s why I chose Linux as my daily driver OS on my personal and work laptop for almost 5 years now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who am I</title>
      <link>https://dheerapat.github.io/posts/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dheerapat.github.io/posts/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>About Myself Hi, internet wanderer. My name is Dheeto. I am an ex-pharmacist currently working as a software engineer in Bangkok, Thailand.&#xA;You might wonder, &amp;ldquo;How come?&amp;rdquo; I ended up in software engineering. Well, let me explain it to you.&#xA;First Few Years of My Career I graduated from pharmacy school in early 2020, the year that COVID-19 hit. The healthcare industry wasn&amp;rsquo;t affected that much, so I could still find a job pretty easily and worked as a laboratory technician for almost three years.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
